American Association of University Professors, U. H. Chapter.
University of Houston Libraries
American Association of University Professors, U. H. Chapter.
1958-1968
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
American Association of University Professors. University of Houston Chapter
1.00 Linear Feet
The University of Houston Chapter of the American Association of University Professors Records arrived at the archives in relatively good order, which has been maintained where possible. The collection consists mainly of documents directly related to the organization including the AAUP Constitution, minutes, bank statements, letters, correspondence, membership lists, and newsletters. For preservation and access reasons the collection has been re-boxed and re-foldered. New folder titles conform, as closely as possible, to original folder titles, except when the original was obviously incomplete, incorrect, or confusing. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
1969-071
Historical Note
The purpose of the University of Houston Chapter of the American Association of University Professors (AAUP) was to "facilitate a more effective cooperation among teachers and research scholars in the university community for the promotion of the interests of higher education and research and in general to increase the usefulness and advance the standards, ideals, and welfare of the profession."
As cited in the organization's Constitution, membership and voting was limited to members of the faculty of the University of Houston who were Active or Emeritus Members and Junior Members of the American Association of University Professors. Associate Members of the American Association of University Professors could be invited to meetings as the Executive Council deemed necessary.
Scope and Contents
The University of Houston Chapter of the American Association of University Professors Records arrived at the archives in relatively good order, which has been maintained where possible. The collection consists mainly of documents directly related to the organization including the AAUP Constitution, minutes, bank statements, letters, correspondence, membership lists, and newsletters. For preservation and access reasons the collection has been re-boxed and re-foldered. New folder titles conform, as closely as possible, to original folder titles, except when the original was obviously incomplete, incorrect, or confusing. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
Forms part of the University Archives.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
American Association of University Professors. University of Houston Chapter; University of Houston
Genre/Form of Material:
Bank statements; Correspondence; Minutes; Newsletters; Records
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition
Detailed Description
- AAUP Material
  - AAUP Constitution (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AAUP Minutes, 1958-59 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AAUP Minutes, 1961-62 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AAUP Minutes, 1961-62 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AAUP Minutes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AAUP Minutes, 1964-65 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AAUP Minutes, 1966-67 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Account Authorization I.D. Card (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bank Statements, 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bank Statements, 1964/65-67 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bank Statements, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chapter Letters, 1958-59 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chapter Letters, 1960-61 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chapter Letters, 1962-63 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chapter Letters, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chapter Letters, 1966-67 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1960-61 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Executive Council Minutes, 1962-64 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Executive Council Minutes, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Finances Bills Paid, 1961-63 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Finances Bills Paid, 1964-66 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Info. for Chapter Officers (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Mailing Addresses (Members) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Membership Applications Reply Forms (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Membership, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Membership, 1960-61 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Membership, 1962-63 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Membership, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Membership, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Membership, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Membership, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Membership no date (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Memo/Notices, 1957-60 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Memos/Newsletters, 1961-62 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Memos/Newsletters/Notices, 1966-68 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - National Membership Brochures (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Notes, Directions Procedures for AAUP (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Planning Committee (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Salary Charts Info. on Academic Salaries, 1960/61-1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Statements of Council Nominees (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Statements on Government and College Universities (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Texas Conference, 1964-66 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1958-60 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - UH Campus Maps (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - West Texas State University-1967 Study of Texas College Libraries (Box 1, Folder 51)